WILLIAM ROBINSON

Full Stack Software Developer

About Me

After 3+ years working as a Civil Engineer and Project Manager, I decided to pursue software engineering. I've always been deeply curious and excited about learning, design and problem solving which led me to join Le Wagon's Software Development Coding Bootcamp in 2022 to accelerate my journey. Throughout my studies I worked with React, Ruby on Rails, Git/Github, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Typescript, APIs, Active Record, SQL Queries and deployed web applications. I am consistently recognized as a hands-on and competent worker who enjoys and flourishes within collaborative work and fast-paced, deadline driven environments.

willjamesr@gmail.com

Melbourne, Victoria

in linkedin.com/in/william-robinson-dev

github.com/willjamesrobinson

Technical Skills



Experience

Lanskey Constructions - Junior Project Manager - Melbourne, Australia - 01 to 09/2022

- Successfully managed the construction of multiple \$5 \$20m commercial buildings, ensuring they were built on time and within budget
- Developed and implemented project schedules, budgets, and quality control measures
- Collaborated with architects, engineers, contractors, clients and other stakeholders to ensure that projects were completed according to specifications and requirements
- Demonstrated strong leaderships skills in managing and motivating teams of construction workers and other professionals to ensure the achievement of key goals
- Maintained healthy relationships with clients and other parties involved in the construction process, leading to repeat business and positive references

City of Mitcham - Project Coordinator/ Project Engineer - Adelaide, Australia - 06/2020 - 01/2022

- Managed the procurement, design and delivery of trades on various projects. Working closely with contractors and consultants to develop construction staffing and logistics plans.
- Reviewed design documentation and provided assistance on the production and review of tender negotiations/evaluations.
- Conducted regular meetings with different project teams, providing progress reports to upper management
- Developed a holistic 10 year plan of the entire councils infrastructure assets, focusing on the renewal of assets based upon condition status and specific product lifecycles

Lendlease - Undergraduate Civil Engineer - Adelaide, Australia - 11/2019 - 01/2020

- Worked alongside a team to tender for the 'Port Wakefield to Port Augusta Project Alliance', a \$300m AUD project for the Augusta Highway upgrade, Port Augusta bridge duplication and construction of the new Port Wakefield overpass.
- Created a histogram to visualise the distribution of staff and labourers for the entire duration of the project, ensuring it encompassed a diverse group of staff.
- Interacted with over 200 contractors, collating documents and quotes.
- Showed innovation with my production of a climate analysis, used to predict the likelihood of days lost due to extreme
 weather circumstances in Port Augusta and Port Wakefield.

Woolworths Group - Team Supervisor - Adelaide, Australia - 2016 - 2020

Managing 20-25 staff members, to whom I provided strong leadership, training and guidance.

Education

Le Wagon Full Stack Software Development Bootcamp - Richmond, Melbourne, 2022

- 10-week intensive coding bootcamp learning Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript ES6, ActiveRecord/SQL, Git, GitHub and Heroku
- Developed full scale applications from concept to completion. Working in an agile scrum environment, our team
 designed and shipped to production a marketplace website

- Learnt to design relational databases and build queries with SQL
- Developed problem-solving skills and the ability to work collaboratively in a team environment
- Completed real-world projects and received feedback and guidance from experienced industry professionals

Bachelor of Engineering (Civil and Architectural) Honours - University of Adelaide, 2016 - 2020

 Awards – Winner of 'Geotechnical Engineering Presentation Prize' at the 2019 Ingenuity Honours Project Presentations.

Web Projects

Zoomies - Social Media Platform for dogs

- Invented, pitched, designed and developed an original project using Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Bootstrap
- Added chat functionality for users to communicate with each other in real-time
- Integrated Mapbox API to display location data and create custom maps enabling users to visualise the location of other users and available dog friendly locations
- Utilized Cloudinary API for image hosting and management
- Used Github for version control and collaboration with other developers
- Deployed the website to a production server for public access

Marketplace Website

- Utilized MVC architecture to develop a fully functional marketplace website using Ruby on Rails
- Implemented user authentication, product listings and chat functionality
- Used Github for version control and collaboration with a team of developers
- Utilized bootstrap and JavaScript for front-end development and design
- Implemented responsive design to ensure the website was optimized for mobile devices
- Deployed the website to a production server for public access

Other Projects

Mundaring Drive Childcare Centre / Bannockburn Shopping Centre

- Helped project manage the construction of a \$5m childcare centre and a \$20m shopping centre. The project spanned across 2500m2 and incorporated a contemporary design
- Management of subcontractors and organising the letting of works to ensure the delivery of the project on time
- Weekly I would meet with the client to answer any questions, discuss variations and explain construction processes.

Jordon Road, Melrose Park Streetscape Redevelopment

- Facilitated and managed a consultation period prior to the commencement of construction with the adjacent allotments along Jordon Rd. This allowed any issues from the business owners to be discussed and rectified before any work began
- Reviewed tenders from varying contractors including pricing schedules, project experiences, fire danger/weather plans, traffic management plans and then proposed program of works to obtain a weighted score.

2021/22 Capital Works Program

- Collated an extensive program for the 2021/22 financial year Capital Works Program
- Forecasted a condition based model using the program 'MyPredictor'. This software used the councils long term
 financial plan budgets, our unit rate library and condition data to produce a program which focused on renewing
 assets with no remaining useful life
- Produced the scheduling of both new and renewal projects across all areas within the City of Mitcham. This included transport infrastructure, property, fleet and open space assets

References

Manon Shearn

City Operations Manager Phone: On request

Piers Duggan

Manager of Engineering Assets, City of Mitcham Phone: On request